别买那个
Don't do it.
那个熟过头了
That one's overripe.
是吗  你能分辨出来吗
Really? You can tell?
相信我
Trust me.
这个才是好的
This is the one...
鲜甜又紧实
sweet and firm.
我喜欢鲜甜的
I like sweet.
也喜欢紧实的
And I like firm.
你在喝什么啊
Aah! What are you drinking,
有毒的废液吗
toxic waste?
我们在做排毒清体
We're doing a cleanse.
他忘了带他的饮品  所以我给送过来
And he forgot his bottle, so I came by to drop it off.
你确定是他忘记了吗
Oh, he forgot it. Are--are you sure?
老实说
Actually,
我这辈子从未这么舒服过
I've never felt better in my entire life.
只喝水和青柠汁  不吃固体食物
Water, lime juice, no solid food.
珍妮和我要排除毒素  一身轻松地举办婚礼
Jenny and I are gonna start our marriage perfectly cleansed.
我们已经进行了一周
We've already made it a week.
再坚持3天就行了
We only have three days to go.
真不敢相信你们俩
I can't even believe you guys
周日就要结婚了
are already getting married on Sunday.
我知道  很不可思议吧
I know. Isn't that crazy?
我得走了  我妈在为座位卡抓狂
I better run. My mom is freaking out about place cards.
到时候见
See you there.
谢了  亲爱的  爱你哦
Thanks, sweetie. I love you.
我爱你更多
I love you more.
那是不可能的
No, that's not possible.
我知道  我知道  我们太恶心了
I know. I know. I know. We're nauseating.
我很期待见到
well, I am looking forward
珍妮联谊会的姐妹们
to meeting some of Jenny's sorority sisters.
让他们看看纽约警察的英姿
I'm about to show them some of New York's finest.
不错  我想那样你就不会在意
Oh, good. Then I guess you won't care
蕾妮带男伴出席婚礼了吧
that Lanie's bringing a plus one.
带谁
Who?
我不知道  她就是回复我说会携伴出席
Uh, I don't know. She just RSVP'd plus one.
怎么  她怎么能立马就有男友了
How can--how can she already have a boyfriend?
我们才刚分手
We just broke up.
别担心  埃斯波  我也是一个人去
Don't worry, Espo. I'm going alone.
要是你泡不到联谊会的女生
So if the sorority girls don't work out,
我会陪你跳舞的
I'll dance with ya.
埃斯波西托
Esposito.
卡塞尔  珍妮说你也要携伴出席
Castle, Jenny tells me that you rsvp'd plus one.
你要带女伴去吗
You're bringing a date?
-是的  -谁啊
- I am. - Who?
这么说吧  她集美丽
Oh... Well, she's beautiful,
智慧  幽默于一身
she's intelligent, she's funny,
她冲我一笑  就能融化我的心
and the way she smiles at me sometimes just melts my heart.
是阿丽克西斯
It's Alexis.
各位
Guys.
有新案子了
We got a fresh one.
蕾妮  是跳楼自杀吗
Hey, Lanie. We got a jumper?
从冲击力来看  他是从七楼以上的
Judging by the impact, I'd say he came from
某个房间掉下来的
one of those windows above the seventh floor.
莱恩和埃斯波西托同旅馆工作人员
Ryan and Esposito are already into finding the room
去找是哪一间了
with the hotel staff.
他全裸唉
So... He's naked.
观察很敏锐嘛
Perceptive.
外面还挺冷的  如果要自杀
Well, it is pretty cold out. If this was a suicide,
穿得温暖舒适点
wouldn't you rather be warm and toasty
再赴这必死无疑的水果劫  不好吗
on your way down to your certain yet citrusy death?
如果这是自杀
If it were a suicide,
会留下这几道
would you really have these...
一个小时前才抓上去的指甲痕吗
fingernail marks, only an hour old?
看来是他跳楼之前还风流了一把
Well, it looks like he did the deed before taking the dive.
或许是遗愿清单上的最后一项
Last item on your bucket list?
两个旅馆员工看到留红色长发的白人女子
Two hotel clerks saw a white lady with long red hair
在裸男摔到水果摊上后急冲冲地离开了
hurrying out shortly after birthday suit hit the fruit.
好  看看能不能
All right, see if you can get
让员工再做更详细地描述
a better description from those clerks,
然后去进行排查
and let's set up a canvass.
我们得找到那个女人
We gotta find that woman.
安东尼奥  能把这些取样放进
Antonio, can you refrigerate these samples
车上的冰箱吗
in the van, please?
-就是这个人吗  -什么
- Is this the guy? - Hmm?
她的男伴
Mr. Plus one.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett!
找到那个房间了
Found the room!
在8楼
Eighth floor!
好
Okay!
用音乐制造气氛吗
Music to set the mood by?
没错
Yeah.
还有枕头上的口红印
And then there's the lipstick on the pillow.
看来蕾妮说对了
Looks like Lanie was right
死者在触及死亡的霉头之前
about our victim getting lucky before he...
才交了好运
ran out of luck.
死者名叫麦克·贝利  28岁
So our vic's name is Michael Bailey, 28,
住在西93号路
lives on West 93rd Street.
从他的名片来看
And according to his business card,
他是市中心环球12联盟的
he's a junior analyst at Global 12 Consolidated
初级分析师
in midtown.
是谁订的房间
Who booked the room?
用简·爱的名字订的
Booked under Jane Eyre.
用现金结账  没有留下信用卡号
Paid with cash. No credit card on file.
意味着这是计划好的
Suggests premeditation.
她知道自己要杀掉他
She knew she was gonna kill him,
所以她用化名订了房间
so she booked the room anonymously.
可为什么要和他发生关系
Yeah, but then why sleep with him?
为什么不直接把他推出窗外就好
Why not just push him out the window?
因为她是个黑寡妇
Because she's a black widow...
世界上最冷血无情的生物
the coldest-hearted creature on earth.
她诱惑一个毫无防范的男人
She lures an unsuspecting male,
将他引到自己网中
takes him into her web,
然后在他们达到高潮的那一刻
and then the moment they culminate,
正当他感受到
as soon as he feels the ecstasy
完成本能使命时的销魂
of achieving his biological destiny,
她就张开血口将他生吞活剥
she opens up her jaws and eats him alive.
我真庆幸我的爱情很健康
I'm glad I'm in a healthy relationship.
没错
Yeah.
我猜雄性的黑寡妇蜘蛛
I bet male black widow spiders
也以为他们的爱情很健康
think they're in healthy relationships, too.
不管是不是黑寡妇
Well, black widow or not,
我想
I think...
我知道该如何找到她了
I figured out how we can find her.
抓到你了
Bingo.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you have any idea who I am?
我是凯勒&布朗&富兰克林公司的合伙创始人
I'm a founding partner of Keller, Braun and Franklin.
我就是富兰克林
I'm Franklin.
我不关心你的法律事务所
Okay. Well, I don't care about your law firm.
有个男人今晚摔死了
A man fell to his death tonight,
指纹证明你曾出现在犯罪现场
and fingerprints confirm that you were at the crime scene.
不  这不关我的事
No, I had nothing to do with it.
也许你能告诉我为什么有人看到
Okay, maybe you can tell me why people saw you
你从犯罪现场逃走
fleeing the crime scene.
富兰克林小姐
Ms. Franklin,
证据显示你和麦克
Evidence suggests that you and Michael...
-麦克  -贝利有肉体关系
- Michael?  - Bailey were romantically involved.
哪个麦克
Michael who?
这个人
This man.
不  他不叫麦克
No, that's not Michael.
他叫杰克  杰克·亨德里克斯
That's Jake. That's Jake Hendricks.
不  他叫麦克·贝利
No, that's Michael Bailey.
我想我知道自己和谁睡了
I think I would know who I was sleeping with.
看起来你并不知道啊
Well, apparently, you don't.
你觉得我该去查她的电话记录吗
You think I should pull her phone records?
何必去查呢
Nah, what's the point?
我们已经掌握她和死者同在旅馆的证据了
We already have her at the hotel with our victim.
不是查她
Not her.
是查蕾妮
Lanie.
什么
What?
不查出那个男人是谁
I'm not gonna go to your wedding
我是不会参加你婚礼的
without knowing who this guy is.
珍妮要写座位卡就必须知道他的名字
Jenny has to find out for the place cards.
我会告诉你的
I'll get you his name.
好
Okay.
他告诉我  他名叫杰克
He told me his name was Jake.
他说他是从芝加哥飞来
Um, he said that he flies in from Chicago
为家族事业谈生意的
to make sales calls for his family business?
他非常贴心
He was really sweet.
我没有杀他
I didn't kill him.
我跟他坠入爱河
I was falling in love with him.
他也"坠"得挺狠的
Well, he fell pretty hard, too.
你们开始约会多久了
So how long were the two of you dating?
其实我们今晚才认识
Uh, well, we, uh, we actually just met tonight.
7点左右  在威尔莫酒吧
Um, at Wilmer's Bar at around 7:00.
今晚
Tonight?
那你就已经和他坠入爱河了
And you were already falling in love with him?
我知道听起来很不靠谱
Look, I-I know-- I know it sounds crazy,
可这就像是传说中的
but it felt like one of those magical connections
心有灵犀  你懂吗
that you read about, you know?
在我们
After we...
那个之后
you know, um,
他开始头晕
he started to get dizzy
汗流不止
and... sweaty.
于是他开窗想呼吸点新鲜空气
So he opened up a window to get some fresh air,
然后他斜靠在窗台边上
and he was leaning against the windowsill
突然间...
when suddenly...
他就...
he just...
那么你是说...
Okay. So you're saying that...
他从窗户上摔下去
He fell out the window
而你的第一反应不是叫救护车
and your first instinct wasn't to call 9-1-1,
而是自己逃跑
but to run away?
我知道你们会怎么想  可是我吓坏了
I knew how it would look, but I panicked
然后做了一个非常糟糕的决定
and I made a really bad decision.
但是我发誓  这绝对只是一起意外
But I swear, it was an accident.
这不是一起意外
It was not an accident.
你能鉴定出他是被推下去的
You can tell he was pushed?
我不是说他是被人推下去的
I didn't say he was pushed.
麦克·贝利被人下毒
Michael Bailey was poisoned
服下了致命剂量的秋水仙素
with a lethal dose of colchicine.
在他摔到水果车上之前就已经死了
He was dead before he hit the fruit.
秋水仙素
Colchicine?
不是一种用来治疗风湿的药吗
Isn't that a drug for rheumatism?
没错  但是贝利没有风湿病
Yes, which Bailey does not have,
而且他体内含有正常值五十倍的药量
but he had 50 times the normal dosage in his system.
我推测他服入药物的时间
I'm putting the time of ingestion
应该在当天下午四点到六点之间
between 4:00 and 6:00 p.m.
那就是霍莉说她们在威尔莫酒吧
Which is 45 minutes before
相遇前的45分钟左右
Holly said she met him at Wilmer's bar.
知道他是怎么服入药物的吗
Any idea how that drug was delivered?
混在他喝的饮料里
It was in something he drank.
我在他的胃里找到很多乳清分离蛋白
I found lots of whey-protein isolate in his stomach,
以及一些巧克力
along with chocolate.
那就是巧克力蛋白奶昔
So a chocolate protein shake.
那种饮料的甜味足以掩盖药物的味道
It'd be sweet enough to mask the taste of the drug.
说到甜  莱恩的婚礼你要带谁作男伴
Speaking of sweet, who's your date for Ryan's wedding?
碰碰运气嘛
Took a shot.
就这样吧  多谢  蕾妮
All right. Thanks, Lanie.
还有一件事
One more thing.
我做了一个DNA测试想证实
I ran a D.N.A. test just to confirm
这位超人先生死前是否与人上床
that superman here had sex before dying--
-不用了  嫌疑人已经...  -让我说完
- No, it's okay. Our suspect... - Let me finish.
测试结果显示他确实与人上床了
The test shows he had sex all right,
而且是跟两个不同的女人
with two different women
都在他死前的几个小时内
within hours of his death.
你这个坏小子
You dog.
富兰克林小姐  看来...
Ms. Franklin, I-it--
看来贝利先生去世之前的几个小时内
It seems that you weren't the only woman that--
你不是唯一一个
that Mr. Bailey was, uh...
跟他在一起的女性
with in the hours prior to his death.
你说的在一起  是什么意思
Um, what do you mean, with?
在酒店里是不是还有一名女性跟你们一起
Was there another woman in the hotel room with you?
我还以为我不可能更丢人了
I didn't think this could get any more humiliating.
-那你是承认了  -当然没有  警探先生
－ Was that a yes? － No, detective.
多谢告知
Thank you.
我应该告诉你我们的法医
Oh, and you should know that our M.E.
鉴定认为贝利先生
has been able to determine that Mr. Bailey
在两次做爱时
was, uh... wearing a condom
都带了安全套  所以...
both times so that's...
真是让我感觉好多了啊
That makes it all better.
现在我倒希望是我亲手推他下去的
Now I wish I pushed him!
女人的怒火真可怕
Hell hath no fury, all right.
但是我十分肯定她没有说谎
But I'm pretty sure she's telling the truth.
可能吧  但是放人之前
Yeah, maybe, but let's just confirm her alibi
再确认一下她的不在场证明
before releasing her.
同时  我们得查明
In the meantime, we need to figure out
下午四点到六点之间
where Bailey was and who he was with
贝利去过哪里  跟谁在一起
between 4:00 and 6:00 p.m. when he was poisoned.
没错
Exactly.
这是凶手的行凶的时间
That is our kill zone.
我找不到他有任何近亲属
So I can't find any next of kin on the guy.
父母在几年前都已过世
Parents died years ago.
没有兄弟姐妹  什么亲人都没有
There's no siblings, no nothing.
你还好吧
You okay?
我很好
Fine.
那贝利告诉霍莉的所有
So then everything Bailey
关于自己的事都是谎言
told Holly about himself was a lie.
可能这就是他的把戏
Mm. Maybe that was his trick.
来自外地  顾家  有事业
In from out of town, family guy, own business--
这样才能骗女人跟他上床
That's how he got women in bed.
不管他为什么要骗霍莉
Whatever his reason for lying to Holly,
我打赌凶手就是贝利之前
I'm betting that our killer is whoever Bailey slept with
睡过的那个女人
earlier in the day.
她发现他玩弄人感情  于是实施报复
She got on to his philandering and got even.
好的  查他的通话记录
All right. Go through his phone records.
我们得找到另外那个女人
We gotta find that other woman.
早上好  爸爸
Good morning, dad.
早上好
Good morning.
亲爱的  你的信用卡放在哪儿
Darling, where's your credit card?
还是"早上好"更顺耳
Mm. Liked "Good morning" better.
问你们俩一个问题
Let me ask you two something. Mm.
如果你们发现自己的男人背叛了你
If you found out a man was cheating on you,
你们会选择怎么杀死他
how would you kill him?
用刀  直插心脏
Knife... to the heart.
好吧  那如果你没有勇气这么做呢
All right. What if you don't have the stomach for that?
-一枪毙命  -你也没有勇气这么做
- Shoot him. But you don't have the stomach for that either.
-我们的勇气到哪儿去了  -总是还能下毒
- What's wrong with our stomachs? - There's always poison.
没错  看着他被痛苦折磨
True. Watch him writhe and suffer.
就像一只牲畜一样死掉
Die like the rodent he is.
这么多年来总是在写凶手的故事
All these years writing about murderers,
竟不知我与她们同住一个屋檐下
I had no idea I was living among them. Well...
说到谋杀  你要我的信用卡做什么
Speaking of murder, what's the credit card for?
我们要去逛街给我买件礼服
Oh, we're going shopping to pick out my dress
好陪你去参加莱恩的婚礼
to be your date at ryan's wedding.
你之前的那些礼服不都很好吗
What's wrong with the ones you have?
亲爱的
Darling,
美丽不是无心插柳得来的
Beauty does not happen by accident.
所以一旦不知好歹的臭男人辜负了我们
And that's why, when it goes unappreciated by cheating scum,
我们定会复仇
we want revenge.
即使是她们虚构的怨气都让人毛骨悚然
Even their hypothetical fury is unnerving.
威廉·康格里夫关于受了侮辱的女人
William Congreve had it right
的言论真是没有说错
when he talked about scorned women.
是吗  你都还没听到过我会怎么做
Yeah, well, you haven't heard what I would do.
我想我还是不知道的好
Yeah, I don't think I ever want to know.
嗨  伙计们
Hey, guys.
关于贝利之前的那个女人找得怎么样了
Hmm? Any luck tracking down Bailey's other woman?
找到不少
Uh... A lot of luck.
有点像《单身汉》[真人秀]的开头
It's like the beginning of "The Bachelor",
只是缺了苹果马丁尼
but without the appletinis.
贝利跟这么多女性都发生过关系
Bailey was involved with all of them?
是啊
Uh, yeah.
而且每个人都觉得自己是他的爱和唯一
And each of them thought that they were his one and only.
这可是不少受到了侮辱的女人啊
That's a lot of scorned women...
而且都有不小的怒火
and a lot of fury.
可是我就是想不明白
Yeah. Yeah, I don't get it.
为什么这样一个长相平凡的男人
H-how does an average looking guy
做着一份普普通通的分析师工作
with a dime-a-dozen analyst job
竟然可以泡到这么多美丽的女人
end up dating all of these gorgeous women?
对她们说谎呗
By lying to them.
实际上  他并没对她们撒谎
Actually, he wasn't lying to these women.
至少关于他的身份他没有说谎
At least not about who he was anyway.
她们都知道他的真名
They all knew him by his real name.
那为什么告诉霍莉他是来自芝加哥的杰克
Then why would he tell Holly that he's Jake from Chicago?
那昨天下午四点到六点之间
Was Bailey with any of those women
贝利有跟她们其中的某位在一起吗
between 4:00 and 6:00 yesterday?
照目前看来  都没有
So far, no.
而且她们都说不知道他居然还在市里
But they all deny knowing that he was even in the city.
一个月前  他告诉她们每个人
A month ago, he told every one of 'em
他要去欧洲呆六个礼拜
he was going to Europe for six weeks.
一个月前
A month ago?
那他为什么提前回来了
So why'd he come back early?
他根本没有去
He never went.
而且从他的信用卡记录来看
And as far as I can tell from his credit card use,
他根本没离开过纽约
he never even left New York.
那为什么要告诉她们自己要离开
So why tell them that he was leaving?
莫非想用一种懦弱的方式跟她们分手
I mean, was that just a cowardly way of breaking up with them?
我觉得另有其他原因
I think there's something else going on.
我打电话到环球12联盟的人事部
I called the personnel department at global 12 consolidated.
他们说他之前一个月
And they said that he's been on a leave of absence
都请了假
for the last month.
这个月有大事啊
That's a big month--
跟单位和女朋友们那儿都请了假
taking a leave from work and your girlfriends.
公寓也没回
And his apartment.
贝利公寓楼的门卫说过去一个月来
The doorman at Bailey's building said that for the past month,
他经常不在家里住
he's only spent a couple nights a week there.
过去的一个月
Past month. Hmm.
是的  他昨天一整天都没回去过
Yeah. He wasn't there at all yesterday,
所以他不是在家里被下毒的
so that's not where he was poisoned.
我翻查了他的镜台
And I looked in his dresser
找到了这个
and I found this.
伊利诺伊州的驾照
Illinois driver's license.
杰克·亨德里克斯  芝加哥市
Jake Hendricks, Chicago.
这就是他告诉霍莉的名字
That's the name that he gave Holly.
那他真的是杰克·亨德里克斯
So he is Jake Hendricks?
不是  他是麦克·贝利  这张是假的
No, he's Mike Bailey. That's a fake.
这肯定不是他在街头随随便便买来的
He did not buy this on some street corner.
这是高仿啊
This is government grade.
连安全全息图都有
Yeah, right down to the security hologram.
他就像是在做卧底
It's like he was living undercover.
我还找到了这个
And I found this.
真是一块不小的蛋糕
That's a lot of cake.
你为什么非得叫它蛋糕  这些就是钱
Why do you have to call it cake? It's money.
很大一笔钱  大约六万美金
It's a lot of money. It's about 60 grand.
现金  假身份
Cash, fake ID.
贝利到底在搞什么
What the hell was Bailey into?
比为了勾搭女人而捏造身份要大的事
Something bigger than lying about who he was just to get laid.
杰克·亨德里克斯有一个假网站
Jake Hendricks has fake web search hits.
住在芝加哥  在家族企业工作
Lives in Chicago, works for the family business.
就像他告诉霍莉·富兰克林的
Just like he told Holly Franklin.
家族企业也有一个假网站
Family business has a fake web site.
这谎编的还挺到位
That's a pretty deep cover.
是的  这位情圣看上去越来越像杰森·伯恩了
Yeah. Our Don Juan's starting to look more like Jason Bourne.
你们去联系联调局和中情局
All right, you guys get ahold of FBI and CIA
还有其他的情报部门
and any other intelligence agency,
看看他是不是他们的人
see if he's one of theirs.
走  卡塞尔  我们去环球12联盟
Come on, Castle. Let's talk to Bailey's boss
找贝利的上司谈谈
at Global 12 Consolidated,
问明死者请假的原因
find out why our vic took that leave of absence.
我们还是需要印度的钍的估价
We still need the estimates on thorium in India.
-而且如果你们能  -不好意思  哈里斯先生
-And I would appreciate- - Excuse me, Mr. Harris.
这两位警探要见你
Those detectives are here for you.
你们介意休息一下吗
You guys mind if we take a few minutes?
没关系
No problem.
反正我们还要讨论次级债务的
We're still working up the financing terms
融资条款
on subordinated debt anyway.
没问题
Sure.
反正我们的谈判也毫无进展
It's not like these negotiations are going anywhere.
麦克是采购部的一名初级分析师
Mike was a junior analyst in our acquisition department.
不错的孩子  前途似锦
He was a good kid, bright future.
我知道他一个月前请了假
I understand that he took a leave of absence a month ago.
他有说是什么原因吗
Did he give you a reason why?
私人事务
Personal issues.
他没说为什么  但我能听出来挺严重的
He didn't say why, but I could tell it was serious.
这么说你不知道他为什么会有
So you have no idea why
假身份和六万美元的现金
he would have a fake ID and $60,000 cash?
不知道
No.
但可能和昨天那个试图
But maybe it had something to do with that woman
闯入他办公室的女人有关系
that tried to break in his office yesterday.
-是谁  -我不知道
- Who was that?  - I don't know.
她在警卫到达之前逃走了
She was gone before security got there.
是谁上报的
And who reported it?
我在谈判中途出来上厕所
I had stepped out of negotiations to go to the restroom.
我注意到走廊里有一个女人
And in the hallway, I noticed a woman was trying
在用扳手和别针
to pick an office door lock
撬一间办公室的门
using a wrench and an opened-up paper clip.
我想她大概是被锁在自己办公室外面了
I assumed she had just locked herself out of her office
就开玩笑说钥匙会比较管用
and joked that a key would work better.
但她被吓了一跳
Well, she was startled
然后推开我冲下楼梯了
and shoved me over and made a dash for the stairwell.
你看到她长什么样子了吗
Did you get a good look at her?
看到了  我告诉警卫了
Yeah, and I told security.
她是外国人  30多岁  黑色卷发
She was exotic, 30-ish, dark, wavy hair.
她穿着一件大衣  但敞开着
She had on an overcoat, but it was open,
她别着一枚六芒星的徽章
and she was wearing a pin with the Star of David on it.
我可以肯定那是以色列航空的徽章
I'm pretty sure it's the insignia from El Al Airlines.
她名字叫科莱特·罗斯
Name's Colette Roth.
27岁
She's 27.
她在以色列航空当乘务员已经三年了
She's been an El Al flight attendant for three years,
飞特拉维夫到肯尼迪机场的航线  一周两次
making the Tel Aviv-JFK. Run twice a week.
情报部门曾用过乘务员担任间谍
Intel agencies used to use flight attendants as spies,
不是吗
didn't they?
是的  还有呢  她在以色列服过役
Yeah, and get this, she's former Israeli military.
以色列情报局最擅长用毒
Mossad is famous for poisoning.
经常用  卡塞尔的杰森·伯恩理论
Yeah, big-time. Castle may not be that far off...
说不定有点道理
with his Jason Bourne theory.
警员正在找她
Uniforms are tracking her down now.
珍妮把蕾妮男伴的名字发给我了
Ah, Jenny just texted me Lanie's plus one.
叫托比·朗
Name is Toby Lang.
什么  托比  好吧
Wh-- what? Toby. All right.
看看他到底什么来头
Let's check this punk out.
托比·朗医生
Dr. Toby Lang?
这家伙是圣塞缪尔医院的行政院长
The guy's the chief administrator at St. Samuel's hospital.
官不小
Big job.
蕾妮不是在这个医院实习的吗
Lanie did her residency there, didn't she?
是的
Yeah.
长得也不错
Good-looking guy.
在肯塔基大学打过篮球
Played college hoops at Kentucky?
癌症研究方面有突破性发现的专家
Groundbreaking cancer researcher?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
帮我也加一个女伴
Put me down for plus one.
珍妮已经确定好座位了
Jenny already did the tables.
还有她联谊会的姐妹呢
What about her sorority sisters?
老兄  我可不想独身赴会
Dude, I'm not showing up solo
而她却带去了个美国队长
when she's bringing Captain America over here.
好的  我会和珍妮说的
Okay, I'll talk to Jenny,
但她妈会问你这张座位卡上要写谁的名字
but her mom is gonna need a name for that place card.
埃斯波西托
Esposito.
知道了
Copy that.
科莱特·罗斯刚刚在肯尼迪机场签到了
Colette Roth just checked in for a flight at JFK.
警员已经去接她了
Unis are picking her up now.
好了
All right.
我不是什么间谍
I'm not a spy.
我只是个乘务员
I'm a flight attendant.
那你可以解释一下你和
Well, then maybe you could explain your relationship
麦克·贝利之间的关系
with Michael Bailey.
他是我的灵魂伴侣
We were soul mates.
那我肯定你能告诉我们
Well, then I'm sure you'll be able to tell us
昨天下午四点到六点之间
where the two of you were yesterday
你们两个在什么地方
between the hours of 4:00 and 6:00 PM.
我在他家外面等他
I was outside his apartment waiting for him.
但他没回来
But he never came.
你昨天一天都没闲着
You had a very busy day yesterday.
在那之前几小时  有人看见你
You were seen trying to break in to his office
试图闯入他的办公室
just hours before that.
我是在试图寻找线索
I was hoping to find some kind of clue,
好让我顺藤摸瓜找到他的仇家
something that might lead me to his enemies.
他的仇家
His enemies?
麦克被人追杀
Michael was a hunted man.
被谁追杀
Hunted, by who?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只知道他遇上麻烦了
I just know he was in trouble.
四个礼拜前  他告诉我他要去欧洲
Four weeks ago, he said he was going to Europe.
但我一直在城里看到他
But I kept seeing him in the city,
他却一直假装没看见我
and he kept pretending not to notice me.
所以我就去监视他的公寓
So I staked out his apartment.
你跟踪了他
So you stalked him?
监视  跟踪  有什么区别
Staked, stalked-- what's the difference?
我是替他担心
I was looking out for him!
但他没有回家
But he wasn't coming home.
过了几天  我跟他对质
Then a few days ago, I finally confronted him.
他说他不方便谈话
He said he couldn't talk,
但是他让我第二天去见他
but he told me to meet him the next day
他会把一切解释清楚
and he'd explain everything.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
之后他就没出现了
That was the last time you saw him.
不  我们第二天见了面
No. We met the next day.
但是他还没来得及说怎么回事
But before he could tell me what was going on,
突然不知从哪冲出一辆车  他们是冲我们而来
this car came out of nowhere, and they were on us.
是谁
Who?
一群头戴面罩的歹徒
Ruffians in ski masks.
他们抓住他扔进车里
They grabbed him and threw him in the back.
我奋力反抗  却没能救得了他
I fought with all of my strength, but it was in vain.
你肯定尽力了
Bet you did.
你报警了吗
Did you report this?
没有
No.
他们说如果我报警就杀了他
They said they'd kill him if I did.
所以我第二天才想要找到他
That's why I was trying to find him the next day,
看他们有没有放他走
to see if they'd let him go.
但是他们杀了他
But they killed him.
那些歹徒把他杀了
The ruffians killed him.
这些是在哪里发生的
Mm-hmm. And where did this all happen?
就在大马路上  光天化日之下
On the street for all to see.
好吧
Okay.
华盛顿和格林威治两条街拐角处
Corner of Washington and Greenwich,
自动提款机的摄像头
ATM cam.
这就是科莱特说绑架发生的地方
This is where Colette said the abduction went down.
但我一直在看  什么都没有
But I've been over it, and there's nothing.
好吧  除非你们喜欢看
All right. Unless you guys are enjoying
无聊的影像
the Warhol-esque quality of this,
我们还是把它关了吧
we can just shut it down.
我去找埃斯波西托  看看他科莱特的
I'm gonna go and check on Esposito, see where he's at
不在场证明查的怎么样了
with Colette's alibi.
等一下
Wait.
贝利出现了
There's Bailey.
这个是科莱特
And here comes Colette.
不是吧
Seriously?
蒙面的歹徒
Ruffians in ski masks.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
科莱特好像打断了那人的鼻子
Looks like Colette just broke that ruffian's nose.
假身份
Fake ID,
大把的现金
bricks of cash,
明目张胆的绑架
brazen abduction...
他真的是杰森·伯恩
he really was Jason Bourne.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
你看不出来吗
Can't you see it?
贝利在执行秘密任务
Bailey is in covert ops.
把他安排在一个巨型跨国公司里
They placed him at a giant multinational company,
即环球12联盟  作为掩护
Global 12 Consolidated, as a cover.
然后一个月前  他们激活了他
Then a month ago, they activate him.
给他一个化名  也就是背景故事
They give him an alias, you know, a backstory.
还有无数的活动资金
They give him unlimited walking-around money,
而之后不知如何
and then somehow
敌人找到了他
the enemy gets to him.
当街将他绑架
They grab him off the streets.
他逃了出来
He manages to escape,
而对方利用他的弱点
so they exploit his achilles' heel-
即喜欢漂亮女人的嗜好
his love of beautiful women.
就派了一名极其性感的特工
They send in a super sexy secret agent.
她引他上钩
She seduces him,
再给他有毒的蛋白质奶昔  置他于死地
and then kills him by feeding him a poisoned protein shake.
我真是想不出更好的解释了
I can't think of anything better.
真的
Really?
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
中情局  联邦调查局
The CIA, the FBI,
和国土安全局从没听说过贝利
and the DHS have never heard of Bailey
或者他的化名
or his alias.
你真的认为若他们知道  会告诉你吗
Do you really think they'd tell you if they did?
技术人员刚刚辨认出绑架者的车牌
Tech just got the plate number off the kidnappers' car.
自动提款机拍下的图像
I thought that the plates
不是看不清车牌吗
weren't visible on the A.T.M. footage.
确实如此  但我发现
They weren't, but I found
前面一个街区的摄像头拍的很清楚
a traffic cam up the block where they were.
车主是个叫巴普罗·贝恩斯的人
Car is registered to a Pablo Barnes,
28岁  保险销售员
28, insurance salesman.
说不定也是个假身份
That's probably a cover, too.
有地址吗
Did you get an address?
当然
Sure did.
很好  我们走
All right. Let's go.
埃斯波哪去了
Where's Espo?
在休息室  想找个女伴
In the break room trying to score his plus one.
埃斯波  该走了
Espo, let's go.
对不起  我...
Sorry. I gotta...
我得走了
I gotta go.
就差这么点就能找到女伴了
I was this close to getting my plus one.
放松  兄弟  谁都碰到这种事
Hey, relax, man. It happens to a lot of guys.
稍微一激动  就忘了手上的蒸汽头
You get a little excited, lose control of your steamer.
纽约警局  把手放在可见处
NYPD! Let me see your hands right now!
纽约警局
NYPD!
不准动  警察
Don't move! Hey, police!
怎么回事  巴普罗
What the hell, Pablo?!
巴普罗·贝恩斯吗
Pablo Barnes?
是  是的  别开枪
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Please don't shoot.
我不知道你们来干什么  但我们是良民
I don't know what you're doing here, but we didn't do anything.
鼻子受伤了  另一个戴面罩的
Broken nose. Other masked man.
埃斯波  也拿下他
Espo, get him, too.
转过身
Turn around!
说真的  我真的不知...
All right, seriously, I don't know why--
你们抓错...
You--you guys have the wrong...
警官  需要绑这么紧吗
Officer, I-I--do they have to be that tight?
这挺疼...
It's very...
《波莱罗舞曲》
"Bolero."
跟在宾馆一样
Just like in the hotel.
瞧  我说我们是狠角色吧
See. I told you we were badass.
那是你的车  巴普罗
That's your car, Pablo.
你跟贝利有什么计划
What were you and Bailey up to,
你又为何杀了他
and why did you kill him?
等下  你是说麦克死了吗
Wait. Are--are you telling me Mike's dead?
别装蒜了  巴普罗
Cut the act, Pablo.
我们知道你两天前绑架了他  为什么
We know you kidnapped him two days ago. Why?
不  不是  事实不是你们看到那样
No, no, no. It's not what it looks like.
那是金蝉脱壳
It's an ex-stalk-tion.
脱什么壳
Ex-stalk-a-what?
麦克是我们的兄弟
Mike's our buddy.
他搞上了这个疯子般跟踪他的女人
He got involved with this crazy stalker chick--
叫科莱特什么的
Colette something--
我们就假扮了一场绑架来吓走她
So we staged an abduction to scare her off.
我们称之为金蝉脱壳
We call it an ex-stalk-tion.
你是说贝利也参与其中
Are you saying, Bailey was in on it?
当然  我们三个是一个团队
Yeah. The three of us are a crew.
什么团队
What kind of crew?
特种部队
Special forces?
私人雇佣军
Private military contractors?
我们是泡妞大师
We're pickup artists.
是指泡女人吗
As in... picking up women?
你吗
You?
我们此生致力于
We dedicate our lives
钓到尽可能多的辣妹
to picking up as many hot women as possible.
这就能解释贝利的那群后宫了
That would explain all of Bailey's women.
公寓里的那些女人都很劲爆
And those girls at the apartment were pretty hot.
播放的那首曲子
That music that was playing,
也是你们的把妹绝招之一吗
is that part of your seduction strategy?
可不是
Oh, yeah.
《波莱罗舞曲》能让
"Bolero" increases the chance
最终滚床单的几率增加12%
of closing the deal by 12%.
假设你讲的都是真话
Okay, assuming that you are telling the truth,
麦克被杀前一晚  你们与他在一起
you were with Mike the night before he was killed.
他告诉过你他的目标吗
Did he tell you what he was up to?
没有  他最近很神秘
Nah. He was being all secretive.
大概一个月前  不再跟我们一起出去
I mean, he stopped hanging out with us, like, a month ago.
是吗  一月前
Really, a month?
当他几天前  打电话来
Yeah, when he called about the ex-stalk-tion
要玩金蝉脱壳
a couple of days ago,
那是近期他第一次跟我们联系
that was the first time we've heard from him since then.
当他说他在金蝉脱壳后要出去玩玩
So when he said he was going out after the ex-stalk-tion,
自然地  我们跟上了他
naturally, we followed him.
他去了哪
Where'd he go?
去了这家非常逊的酒吧  魔瓶
He went to this totally lame bar--the Magic Bottle.
根本没什么靓女
I mean, not target-rich at all.
等他发现我们也在
Oh, and when he found us there,
就有点慌了  但他还是同意
he kinda freaked, but he agreed
让我们待着  帮他把妹
to let us stay and be his wingmen,
但要求我们叫他杰克
But only if we referred to him as Jake,
好像在干卧底似的
like he was undercover.
杰克  正是他第二天
Jake. That's the same identity
告诉霍莉·富兰克林的名字
he gave to Holly Franklin the next day.
我们上演了几个绝招
So we do our usual couple laps of recon.
事实上  确实有几个不错的熟女
Actually, some pretty decent milfs.
我还以为麦克是想换换口味
and I think Mike's just expanding his palate, right?
但他对其中任何一个都不感兴趣
But he wasn't interested in any of them.
其实  他找到了一个目标
No. Instead, he finds this one mark,
根本没什么特别的
like, ugh, nothing special,
便决定下手
and plants his flag.
我发现她手上戴着戒指
Then I see that she's got a ring on her finger.
她是个结了婚的女人
She's a married chick.
我们从不招惹结了婚的
We stay away from married chicks.
你们还真有道德感
'Cause you're so ethical.
才不是  因为她们太麻烦
No. They're just trouble.
但他却不在乎
But he doesn't care.
他一门心思找上她
He's all in on her.
你认为他是为了这个女人到这间酒吧
So you think he went to this bar for this particular woman,
好像他早就瞄好了
like he was targeting her?
正是
Exactly.
他说为什么了吗
Did he say why?
没  但他使劲浑身解数
No, but he was working her
好像生死在此一举似的
like his life depended on it.
就好像这是他的任务
I mean, it was like he was on a mission.
她有上钩吗
Did she go for him?
没  完全不搭理
Nah, total red light.
栏杆下  火车到  该换个目标了
Gate's down, train's coming, time to move on.
但麦克不这么认为
But not Mike.
那晚不是
Not on this night.
那他做了什么
So what did he do?
他使出"满不在乎"
He counters with some authorizing.
满不在乎
Authorizing?
就是表现的好像
You know, making it seem like
他完全没有其他念想
the last thing on his mind is hooking up.
他只是觉得她有意思  想聊聊天
He just finds her interesting and wants to talk.
但她还不上钩  他就使出"移情换位"
But she doesn't bite, so he tries an m-swig.
告诉她  他认识的一个女孩背叛了他朋友
Tells her he knows this girl who's cheating on his friend.
他该不该告诉他朋友
Should he tell his friend?
女人总是喜欢给别人建议
'Cause women love to give advice,
但她还是没给他好脸色
But she's still giving him the heisman,
他便来招声东击西
So he tries a butter job.
怎么个声东击西法
A butter job, what's that?
就是跟目标的朋友调情
It's when you flirt with the mark's friend.
这时终于引来她的注意
and that's when he started getting traction.
随即使出"欲擒故纵"
Immediately follows with a yank-and-chain reversal,
看看她是否真的上钩
sees he's got her on the hook.
他再拿出贝利的杀手锏
So he goes right for the Bailey ultimatum.
来了  他的绝招
Boom! Signature move.
说他要走了
Says he has to leave,
迫使目标迅速做决定
forcing the mark to make a quick decision
是否要一起离开
whether to go with you or not.
-那她怎么做的  -下一幕便是
- And what did she do? - Next thing you know,
两人一起离开那家酒吧
the two of them are walking on their way outta there.
你的眼睛真美
You know, you have some beautiful eyes.
不是吧
Seriously?
怎么了  这就是个几率问题
What? It's a numbers game.
90%的情况下都不会成功
I strike out 90% of the time.
女人还是很有判断力的
Thus restoring my faith in my gender.
他下手的这个女人
So this mark that he was working,
知道她的名字吗
does she have a name?
丽莎
Lisa.
这是我见过的最成功的泡妞战术
The greatest pickup I have ever seen.
真可惜她没能上麦克的花名册
It's a damn shame she'll never make it into Mike's ledger.
什么花名册
What ledger?
里面是上百个贝利睡过的女人
It's literally hundreds of women that Bailey slept with.
他吹嘘吧
Or so he claims.
我觉得挺可信的
It seems legit to me.
都是艳照门级别的照片唉
Most of these shots are pretty racy.
都注有别名和日期
All with nicknames and dates.
2010年6月9日  "浪荡卡莉"
June 9, 2010, "Carnal Carrie."
2010年6月12日
June 12, 2010,
"神魂颠倒的玛珍"
"Mesmerizing marjan."
抱歉
Whoa. Sorry.
这上面两天前有一个叫丽莎的吗
Is there a Lisa in there from two days ago?
没有  最后一人是一个月前
Uh, no. The last entry was over a month ago.
巴普罗没说错  她确实不在里面
So Pablo was right, she didn't make it in.
我们得找到丽莎
We gotta find Lisa.
她可能就是我们要找的人
She could be our other woman.
麦克斯和巴普罗的不在场证明得到证实
Hey, so our friends Max and Pablo just alibied out.
麦克被下毒时  他们都在工作
They were both at work when Mike was poisoned.
"柔韧骨露西"
"Limber Lucy."
瞧瞧  形容得真贴切
And, boy, is she ever.
我不知道贝利是在干什么
I don't know what this dude Bailey was into,
但无论是啥  他真有一手
but whatever it is, he had it going on.
真的吗  这就让你艳羡了
Really? This impresses you?
掉入他陷阱的这些女人真是可怜
These women are pathetic for falling for this guy.
至于贝利  他就是个花心萝卜大骗子
And Bailey, Bailey was just a-a con man and a liar.
谢谢  至少我们中还有个像样的男人
Thank you. At least there is one real man amongst us.
莱恩  为何不带上"状况哥"
Ryan, why don't you take the situation
去魔瓶酒吧询问一番
down to the Magic Bottle
看看能否找出丽莎这个人
and see if we can get an I.D. on Lisa
以及贝利把她作为目标的原因
and find out why Bailey might have been targeting her?
贝克特  莱恩和珍妮到底什么时候开始约会的
Beckett, when exactly did Ryan and Jenny start dating?
我记得大概是2009年吧
I think it was around 2009.
她送给他一条奇丑的领带作为两周纪念礼物
She got him that ugly tie for their 2-week anniversary,
应该是四月复活节
So, like, easter, April.
就是说在2009年5月
Meaning, by may 2009,
他们已经交往一个月了
they had been dating a month.
是的  怎么了
Yeah, why?
贝利在2009年5月20日的记录
Bailey's May 20, 2009 entry.
我的天  是珍妮
Oh, my gosh. That's Jenny.
不仅仅是珍妮
Not just Jenny.
还是"旋舞珍妮"
"Gyrating Jenny."
我记得他
Yeah, I recognize him.
两天前和几个朋友来过这
In here with a couple of friends two nights ago.
他朋友说他跟一个女人一起离开了
One of those friends told us that he left with a woman.
-丽莎  你知道她是谁吗  -知道
- Lisa. Do you know her? - Yeah.
-她是常客  -她姓什么
- She's a regular. - Does she have a last name?
让我找一下
Give me a sec.
我挺喜欢这里的  兄弟
I think I like this place, partner.
伙计  你是个警察
Dude, you're a cop.
这种市中心的酒吧
This is a midtown bar.
来这的女人  都是冲着律师和银行家
Women here, they're looking for lawyers and bankers.
我也存存款啥的
I bank.
你自己折腾去吧
Well, you are on your own.
我周日就要结婚了
I'm getting married on Sunday.
正因这样
Exactly.
这是你做我的泡妞搭档的最后机会
So this is your last chance to be my wingman.
帮我找个女伴
Help me get a plus one.
我觉得我可以试试"移情换位"
I think I'm gonna try an m-swig.
老兄  你别开玩笑了
Dude, you can't be serious.
那你说呢  "声东击西"吗
What are you thinking, butter job?
我查了那晚是信用卡收据
I checked credit card slips from the other night.
她叫丽莎·希尔
Her name's Lisa Hill.
丽莎·希尔
Lisa hill.
丽莎·希尔不仅已婚
So not only is Lisa Hill married,
她还是个富婆
she is also an heiress--
史黛芬妮·达斯比的女儿
Daughter to Stephanie Dashby.
达斯比出版集团吗
Of Dashby publishing?
她在福布斯富豪榜上也是榜上有名
Which puts her in Forbes top 400.
贝利这回胃口可不小
Bailey was hunting big game.
他知道初级分析员的身份不够水准
He knew he couldn't close the deal as a junior analyst,
所以就用了化名
that's why he used the alias with her,
跟搭上名流律师霍莉·富兰克林的手法如出一辙
same way he used it with big-shot lawyer Holly Franklin.
根据她女仆的证词
Yeah, well, according to her maid,
丽莎·希尔收拾了行李
Lisa Hill packed up and left her apartment
在晚上六点半离开了在蒙托克的公寓
for her house in Montauk at 6:30 p.m..
下毒时间区的半小时后
Half an hour after our kill zone.
而且她很容易便能搞到毒药
Plus she also had easy access to our poison.
她的姐姐有一家制造此药的制药厂
Her sister owns a drug company that manufactures it.
一切都是钱引起的
This is about the money.
贝利只有在接近霍莉和丽莎
Bailey only used the Jake identity
这两个富婆时  才用杰克这一身份
with Holly and Lisa. They're both rich.
所以你认为这是个敲诈骗局吗
So what are you thinking, an extortion plot?
那些现金  可能是之前得手的
Bricks of cash--probably from previous successes.
他以富有的女人为目标
He targets wealthy women,
试图让她们陷入困境
tries to put them in compromising situations...
然后再敲她们竹杠
And then makes them pay their way out...
不过丽莎·希尔不愿出钱
Except Lisa Hill wouldn't pay.
我们要找她来问话
We need to get her in here.
当然要
And we will...
明早第一件事
First thing in the morning.
对了
So...
我们怎么办
What are we gonna do?
什么事
About what?
我们得把珍妮的事告诉莱恩
Well, we have to tell Ryan about Jenny.
什么  为什么啊
What? Why?
卡塞尔  如果是我们即将结婚
Castle, if we were getting married, would you want to know
你想知道所有跟我有过关系的男人吗
about all the guys that I've slept with?
所有吗
All?
没搞错吧
Seriously?
你在签售会上都签在女读者的胸上
You sign women's chests at book readings.
我不是处女你总不会很讶异吧
You cannot be shocked that I'm not a virgin.
我只是觉得"所有"这词
It's just the word... "all"
意味着
suggests
有很多
a lot.
到底有多少人
How many are we talkin'... exactly?
你真的想知道我的数字吗
Are you really asking for my number?
你告诉我  我也告诉你  平等交易
You show me yours, I'll show you mine.
男人啊
Men.
总是嘴上说想知道
You all want to know,
但知道了就后悔
but you don't want to know.
听着  每个女人都有秘密
Listen, every women has their secrets,
珍妮也是  而且有时
including Jenny, and sometimes,
为了维系感情  还是不追根究底为妙
for the sake of a relationship, it is better not to share.
真是件漂亮的礼服
That is some dress.
她是不是很迷人
Isn't she stunning?
在逛了一天无果后
After striking out all day,
终于去了麦迪逊的JDF
we finally tried J.D.F.'s on Madison.
绝对是去对地方了
And, boy, did we score.
听起来不单是买到裙子这么简单啊
Well, that sounds like it's about more than just a dress.
不仅阿丽克西斯
Well, not only did Alexis find
找到了这件绝美的裙子
this exquisite little number,
我们也被店主人深深吸引了
we were completely charmed by the proprietor--
约翰·丹顿·法沃斯
John Danton Farnesworth.
JDF
J.D.F.
我们付款时
So as we're paying,
法沃斯正准备关门
Mr. Farnesworth is about to close up,
这时他的孙子
when his grandson,
约翰·丹顿·法沃斯三世
John Danton Farnesworth III,
来接他吃晚餐
picked him up for dinner.
这位JD很帅
Goes by J.D. So cute.
是位很讨人喜欢的男孩
Oh, he is a lovely young man--
在哥伦比亚大学读大一
Freshman at Columbia.
我也正在申请
Which I'm applying to,
所以我问了他不少问题
so of course I grilled him about it.
而接下来
And the next thing you know,
就邀请我们一起吃晚餐
they invite us to join them for dinner.
哪个是泡妞搭档
So who was the wingman,
祖父还是孙子
the grandpa or the kid?
什么啊
The what?
爸爸
Dad,
他们绝对是绅士
they were total gentlemen.
还邀请我们参加他们家的年度慈善活动
They even invited us to their family's annual charity event--
Lady Gaga的私人演唱会
a private concert with Lady Gaga.
但跟婚礼的时间有冲突
But it's the same time as the wedding.
我知道我答应过你
I know, I promised,
当然如果你需要我还是会陪你  只是
and of course I'll go if you want me to, it's just--
自阿什利之后  我头一次有这种感觉
this is the first time I've felt this way since Ashley,
而且...
And...
你不用去婚礼
You don't have to go to the wedding.
-不用来做我的女伴了  -谢谢爸爸
- You are released from your plus one duties. - Thanks, dad.
也就是说你也不需要这件礼服了
Which I guess means you don't need this dress.
别犯傻了  儿子
Don't be silly, darling.
那可是正装慈善活动
It is a black-tie benefit.
在晚餐后
And after dinner,
约翰重开店门
John opened the shop...
我也买了一件
and I got one, too.
还真是双赢啊
So it's a win-win.
我不敢相信你背弃了我
I can't believe you bailed on me.
我们在那待到了凌晨两点半
We were there till 2:30 in the morning.
我再要五分钟  就能让她
Yeah, I was five minutes from sealing the deal
来做我的女伴了
with my plus one.
我们都待了三个小时了
You really think after standing there for three hours,
你真的觉得再多五分钟
another five minutes of me standing there
就能结果不同吗
would've made any difference?
当然  她对我有意思
Yeah. She was into me.
她说她觉得破案"挺有趣的"
She said that she thought solving murders was "cute."
但你也不用告诉她朋友你订婚了
Yeah, but you didn't have to tell her friend you were engaged.
是的  你说的对
Oh, no, no, you're right.
我完全可以瞒着她
I could've totally just-- just lied to her
同她鬼混
and hooked up with her.
你非得这样老套吗
And do you have to be such a cliche?
把吃的东西弄得满嘴都是
Stuffing your face with that-- that--that thing?
别碰我的甜甜圈
Hey, don't touch my doughnut.
-莱恩  -在我面前吃这个  我受够你了
- Hey, Ryan. - Eat this in front of me. I've had enough of you!
你
Don't you--don't you--
别打了
Break it up.
到底发生什么事了
Guys! What the hell is going on?
问这个先动手的饿死鬼
Talk to hunger strike over here.
他不停地炫耀嘴里的甜甜圈
He was flaunting that doughnut.
我只是在吃而已
I was eating it.
莱恩  你还好吗
Ryan, you okay?
禁食九天
A cleanse for nine days--
你认为是时候放弃了吗
Don't you think it's time to let it go?
不不不  我可以的
No, no, no. I'm--I'm fine.
我很抱歉  对你们每个人  对不起兄弟
I'm--I'm sorry, everybody. Sorry, bro.
找到丽莎·希尔没
So any luck finding Lisa Hill?
我们在蒙托克的一家温泉会所找到她了
Yeah, we tracked her down at a spa in Montauk.
她踏出矿质泥潭卷入谋杀漩涡
Yeah, she's going from mud wrap to murder rap,
表皮脱落之后就来接受讯问
exfoliation to interrogation,
修完指甲之后就被铐上手铐
manicure to manacles,
指压按摩之后
shiatsu to...
Shiatsu...
指压按摩之后
警员去带她过来了
Unis are on their way to pick her up now.
你认识他吗  希尔小姐
Do you recognize him, Ms. Hill?
认识  他是杰克
Yes, it's Jake.
是的  是杰克·亨德里克斯
Yes, Jake Hendricks.
准确地说  你以为是
Or so you thought,
直到你发现他真名其实是麦克·贝利
until you found out his real name was Michael Bailey.
他勒索你
And he was trying to blackmail you.
我说的对吗
Isn't that right?
勒索
Blackmail?
我真搞不懂你在说什么
I...don't know what you're talking about.
我想你懂的
I think you do.
你发现你被玩弄了
You realized that you had been played,
决心要报复
and you decided to take your revenge.
你姐姐有家制药厂对吗
Your sister owns a, um, a drug company?
你用来毒死他的秋水仙碱
She must have given you the colchicine you used
肯定是你姐姐给你的  对吗
to poison him, didn't she?
不  没有
Uh, no.
我没有报复
Look, I didn't get revenge
因为我压根不知道他在打什么主意
because I never knew what he was up to.
但他的确在打主意
But he was up to something.
当他在酒吧
I should've realized
使出浑身解数跟我搭讪我就该意识到的
when he was hitting on me so hard at the bar.
但他善解风情
But he was cute,
而我丈夫爱工作甚于
and my husband is more interested in work
爱生活  所以
than actually living, so...
我就带他回家了  感觉真不错
I brought him home, and it was nice.
但当我洗完澡出来时
But then I came out of the bathroom,
发现他在查看电脑
and caught him on the computer.
我想他肯定是在偷信用卡
I figured he was trying to steal credit cards
银行户头信息
banking info,
就把他赶出去了
so I kicked his ass out.
但我发誓  那是我最后一次见他
But I swear, that was the last time I saw him.
贝利给自己发了封电子邮件
Bailey sent an e-mail, all right, to himself.
为什么他要给自己发邮件
Why would he e-mail himself?
因为他在希尔的电脑上找到了几份文件
Because he attached several documents from Hill's computer.
什么文件
What kind of documents?
机密文件
Confidential ones...
关于KPM矿业公司的
relating to K.P.W. Mining corporation.
丽莎·希尔的丈夫罗恩·希尔
Lisa Hill's husband Ron Hill
是代理KPM公司可期待销售业务
is the investment banker representing K.P.W.
的投资银行家
on the possible sale of the company.
他是丽莎·希尔的丈夫
That's Lisa Hill's husband?
我们环球12联盟的办公室见过他
We saw him at the Global 12 offices.
罗恩·希尔代理KPW谈生意
Yep, and Ron Hill is representing K.P.W.
那可是价值数十亿的买卖
It's a multibillion-dollar deal.
那么贝利的确参与了秘密行动
So Bailey was engaged in covert ops.
他找上了罗恩·希尔的妻子丽莎
He targeted Ron Hill's wife Lisa,
同她上床从而偷到KPW公司的商业机密
slept with her in order to steal K.P.W. Corporate secrets.
他是商业间谍
That's espionage.
更像是性间谍活动
More like sexpionage.
更像动机
More like motive.
贝利利用其泡妞绝技
So Bailey was using his pickup artist skills
睡了罗恩·希尔的妻子
to sleep with Ron Hill's wife
偷到了公司机密
and steal corporate secrets.
让我想起了"深入敌后"的笑话
Man, there's a "penetrating enemy lines" joke here somewhere.
罗恩发现那些文件被偷后
You know, Ron must have hit the roof
肯定勃然大怒
when he discovered that those files were stolen.
这当然  罗恩在交易中被坑了
Oh, sure. Ron got screwed on the deal.
他妻子还被别人上了
And his wife got screwed.
要说谁有杀人动机  肯定是罗恩·希尔
Boy, if anybody ever had a motive for murder, it was Ron Hill.
只不过投毒谋杀时间区内
Yeah, except he was in negotiations
他正在谈判
during the poison-and-kill zone
他妻子丽莎的不在场证明也被核实了
and his wife Lisa alibied, too.
我查了KPW的交易
Anand I've been lookin' at the K.P.W. deal
发现由凯勒&布朗&富兰克林公司
turns out that they're represented
代理他们的法律事务
by Keller, Braun and Franklin.
猜猜谁是首席律师
Guess who their lead attorney is?
霍莉·富兰克林
Holly Franklin?
是的  就是酒店那位
Yep, Miss no-tell-hotel herself.
你们没在环球12联盟遇见她是因为
The only reason you guys didn't run into her
当时她被我们扣留在警局
at Global 12 Consolidated is that we were still holding her.
那就解释了丽莎同霍莉的联系
That explains the Lisa and Holly connection.
是啊  这也引出了新的问题
Yeah, but it begs the question,
在这场性间谍行动中
how many other women did Bailey target
到底还有哪些女人是贝利的目标
in this little sexpionage scheme?
你俩去弄一份所有参与KPW
All right, you guys get a list of all the people at K.P.W.
交易的人员名单
that were working the sale,
-包括投资和法律团队  -好的
- including the banking and legal teams. - Right.
贝利不可能单独行动
There's no way that Bailey was working this alone.
他还太嫩
He's too junior.
而且
And besides,
他在休假
he was on leave.
谁批准的假期
And who authorized the leave?
是的  是我批准他休假的
Yes, I authorized his leave.
哈里斯先生  你给他提供了假身份证和现金红利
You gave him a fake I.D. and cash bonuses, Mr. Harris.
我跟你说过了  我对那毫不知情
And I've already told you, I don't know anything about that.
好吧  那这呢
Okay, well, how about this?
贝利为了你的谈判同霍莉·富兰克林和
Bailey slept with Holly Franklin and Ron Hill's wife Lisa
罗恩·希尔的妻子丽莎上床从而窃取KPW的商业机密
to steal K.P.W. secrets for your negotiation.
你对此知情吗
Did you know about that?
哈里斯  别装了
Oh, come on, Harris.
这不可能是贝利这菜鸟的主意
This couldn't be Bailey's idea.
你是他老板  同时也是同KPW交易中
You're his boss, and you're Global 12 Consolidated's
代表环球12联盟的首席谈判员
lead negotiator for the K.P.W. deal.
那么
So...
你是怎么想到这点子的
How did it start?
碰巧某晚你撞见贝利在酒吧
Did you happen to see Bailey out one night at some bar,
施展泡妞大法
working his magic,
使你意识到可以利用他的能力
realized that you could use his ability to your advantage?
那不过是你的胡乱猜测
That is nothing but wild speculation.
你没有证据证明我或是环球12联盟
You have no proof whatsoever of any wrongdoing on my part
有不道德行为
or Global 12.
听着  我才不关心公司渎职
Look, I don't care about corporate malfeasance.
我只想找出杀死麦克·贝利的凶手
I want Michael Bailey's killer.
你怎么知道我能帮上忙呢
And how do you think I can help?
你告诉我他上个月住在哪
You tell me where he's been staying for the past month,
告诉我他的目标还有谁
tell me who else was targeted,
在被杀那天他跟谁在一起
and who he was with the day that he was killed.
除非你要控告我什么罪名
Unless you're actually gonna charge me with something...
否则我现在就要走了
I'm leaving.
KPW有超过三百名女性高管
There are more than 300 female executives at K.P.W.
贝利有可能对其中任何一个下手
Bailey could have targeted any one of them.
更别提与交易有关的在律所和
Not to mention all the women at the law firm
投资银行工作的女性了
and the investment bank who are also working on the deal.
我们对他在哪被下毒还一无所知
And we still have no idea where he was poisoned.
有发现吗
Any luck?
没  可能同贝利睡过的女人太多了
Nope. There's too big a pool of possible marks
无从下手
that Bailey could've slept with.
说起这个
Yeah, uh, speaking of that,
你们知道
You know...
莱恩是我兄弟
Ryan's my boy,
所以我打算把珍妮和贝利的事告诉他
so I gotta tell him about Jenny and Bailey.
你只让我别告诉莱恩
You only told me I couldn't tell Ryan.
埃斯波  我同意你的观点
Look, Espo, I appreciate your point of view,
但他已经禁食一周半了
but the guy hasn't eaten in a week and a half.
而且在发生了甜甜圈事件后  我不
And after that doughnut incident, I don't...
我把文件拿到我桌上去看
I'll just take this back to my desk.
坐下  兄弟
Sit down, bro.
怎么了
What?
你们怎么这么严肃
Why do you guys look so serious?
你应该吃点东西
You should... eat something.
对  你看起来饿极了
Yeah. You look hungry.
你就像只找食的流浪猫
You've got the posture of a feral cat.
我对我爱的女人发过誓的
Guys, I made a sacred vow to the woman I love.
-那是木须肉吗  -是
- Is that moo shu pork? - Yes.
好吃极了  兄弟  吃点吧
And it is delicious. Come on, bro. Just eat.
你真没骗我
You aren't kidding about this moohuhu pork.
-好吃  -对吧
- Come on! - Right?
把那春卷也递给我
Passing the spring rolls, please.
那个...
So...
你知道我们都很爱珍妮  对吧
you know how we all love Jenny, right?
知道  怎么了
Yeah, what about her?
就是那个
It's just that....
贝利的那个花名册
that ledger of Bailey's....
珍妮在里面吗
Is she in that?
我早就想问你们了  可是
I've been meaning to ask but
我最近记忆力不怎么样
I've been having these these memory lapses.
把炒饭递给我
Pass the fried rice.
这么说你早就知道咯
So you've known all along?
我昨晚在跟珍妮讲哈维尔的囧事
No, I was telling Jenny about Javier's antics last night....
然后就聊到了这个案子
and we got to talk about the case.
然后她跟我说  我们刚开始约会了一个月左右
And she told me that she met Bailey at a bar
她曾在一间酒吧里遇到了贝利
a month or so after we started up.
她居然还告诉你这事
She told you about that?
是啊  她根本不知道
Yeah. She had no idea
他居然是个什么泡妞大师
that he was some kind of professional pickup artist.
而你居然完全不生气
And you're not upset at all?
拜托  我们当时还没正式确立关系
Hey, um, it's not like we were exclusive.
那是蒙古牛肉吗
Is that Mongolian beef?
天啊
Oh, man.
谢谢  多特
Oh. Thanks, Dot.
听好咯  我一直想查清楚
Get this. So I've been trying to figure out
贝利在过去的这一个月中
where else Bailey might have been staying
还有可能待在哪
for the past month,
当我们发现他在给他的公司
and when we got on to his corporate spying
环球12联盟做间谍时
for Global 12 Consolidated,
我就去调查了他们公司的住房
I looked into their corporate housing.
真是个好主意
That's a great idea.
就是啊  我怎么没想到呢
Yeah. Why didn't I think of that?
结果发现过去的一个月以来
Turns out Mike Bailey has been checked in
麦克·贝利一直用他的假名杰克·亨德里克斯
to the Oaks on Park Avenue for the last month
住在派克大街的橡树大厦
under his alias Jake Hendricks.
那你还坐在这儿干吗
Well, what are you sitting around for?
我把剩下那块排骨带走吃行吗
Oh. Uh, do you mind if I take the spare rib?
没问题
Okay.
你们可以随便看
You're welcome to look.
但是我们昨天接到了电话
But we got the call yesterday,
亨德里克斯不会回来了
Mr. Hendricks wasn't coming back.
他的东西你们是怎么处理的
What'd you do with all his stuff?
根据他公司的要求  我们把他的衣物
Per his company's instructions, we gave his clothes
和私人物品都捐给慈善机构了
and personal belongings to goodwill,
这个房间也都请人来打扫过了  床单也都换过了
and the place has been scrubbed, bedding laundered.
哈维尔  看看这个
Hey, Javier, check this out.
巧克力旋风
Chocolate blast.
这是蛋白质饮品
It's a protein shake.
原料是乳清分离蛋白
"Made with whey-protein isolate."
你们一直把这种饮品放在冰箱里吗
You always stock this drink?
是的  这都是标准配备
Yeah. It's all standard.
蕾妮说导致贝利中毒死亡的秋水仙碱
It's exactly what Lanie said that Bailey had in his system
正是混在这种饮品里的
that delivered the colchicine.
他就是在这里被人下毒的  兄弟
This is where he was poisoned, bro.
看来我们找到凶器了
Looks like we found the murder weapon.
蕾妮说从橡树大厦拿回来的巧克力奶昔的成分
Lanie says that the chocolate shake from the Oaks
与贝利胃里的残留物成分
is a perfect match for the contents
完全匹配
of Bailey's stomach.
这就是掺有致命剂量的秋水仙碱的饮品
It's what delivered the lethal dose of colchicine.
橡树大厦的门卫已经证实了
So the doorman at the Oaks confirms
贝利在预测投毒时间内一直待在他的房间里
that Bailey was there during the whole poison time window.
他叫人不要打扰他
He asked not to be disturbed.
那是肯定的了  因为性间谍活动
Yeah, I bet, because sexpionage
可比普通的间谍活动费时费心
can be so much more demanding than espionage.
这倒是
True.
那也就是说有人来访
So I'm guessing he had a visitor.
是的  这个人以前也曾去过好几次
Yep, someone who had been there a few times before.
这是监控摄像头拍到的照片
Security cam photo capture.
眼熟吗
Look familiar?
如果我们专注于第三季度的话
If we could focus on the third quarter,
相信将能以
I believe that would be
最有成效的方式推动进展
the most productive way to move forward.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
抱歉再度打扰了
Sorry to interrupt again.
怎么了  赛斯
What's up, Seth?
没事  什么事都没有
Nothing. Nothing at all.
探长  我已经把我对麦克·贝利
Look, detective, I have already told you
所了解的一切都告诉你了
everything that I know about Michael Bailey.
所以请你们
Now please...
离开吧
leave.
实际上  我们不是来找你的  哈里斯先生
Actually, we're not here for you, Mr. Harris.
不过我们过会儿就会要找你了
That would be the S.E.C, soon.
今天
Today...
我们是来找一位女士的
we are here for a woman,
一位KPW的雇员
someone who works for K.P.W.
她还认识麦克·贝利
and also knew Michael Bailey --
也就是你的首席运营官  艾米·坎普
your C.O.O, Amy Kemp.
你因谋杀麦克·贝利而被捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Michael Bailey.
很高兴与你合作  赛斯
Pleasure doing business with you, Seth.
走吧
Let's go.
她说"杀他只是为公事"
She said "killing him was just business".
为了保护商业机密  他必须死掉
He had to die to protect the corporate secrets.
是啊  我想他不能再到处
Yeah, I guess the fact that he won't be around
骗其他的女人算是附加的好处了
to dupe other women was an added benefit.
贝利对她使了他对所有女人都使的那套把戏
Bailey worked her like all the other women --
让她以为自己是特别的
made her feel special,
使她爱上了他  但是就在这个过程中
got her to fall for him -- but somewhere along the way,
她发现了他的真实目的
she figured out what he was up to.
我真是庆幸我不用再玩那套把戏了
I'm just glad I'm out of the game.
我的朋友  对于你  这套把戏才刚刚开始
The games are only beginning for you, my friend.
你找到婚礼的女伴了吗
Hey. So what's up with your plus one?
较上劲了
Oh, it's on.
我目前只能透露这么多
That's all I'm sayin'.
蕾妮
Lanie. Hey.
你好呀  哈维尔
Hello, Javier.
这位是托比
This is Toby.
很高兴认识你
Pleased to meet you.
我也是
Yeah, you, too.
这位是乔迪
This is Jody.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
我也是
Pleasure.
-不好意思  我要去一下洗手间  -好的
- Excuse me. I need to find the ladies room.  - Okay.
你们俩聊吧  我去找座位
Uh, you two talk. I'll get us seats.
谢谢  托比
Thank you, Toby.
托比啊
Toby, huh?
什么意思  什么叫"托比啊"
What do you mean, "Toby, huh?"
不知道  该问你啊
I don't know. You tell me.
咱俩两个月前就分手了
You and I broke up two months ago,
除非你认为我准备这辈子做修女
so unless you thought I joined a convent,
不然你最好还是别搀合
you need to take a step back.
-这么说你们俩是来真的了  -没错
- So you two serious now?  - Yeah, we're serious...
我们都真的很热爱跳舞
Mm-hmm. About dancing.
所以他男朋友才肯把他借给我
That's why his boyfriend let me borrow him.
再说了  我心想你跟珍妮的那些
Besides, I figured I'd need somebody to keep me company
联谊会姐妹们打情骂俏时  我最好有人作伴
while you flirted with all of Jenny's sorority sisters.
托比的男朋友
Toby's boyfriend?
而且我好像也看见你
And I seem to recall you here
带着位大美女来了呀
with the center for the New York Liberty.
她是我表妹
She's my cousin.
我听说你要带男伴来
I heard you were coming with a date,
所以我想我怎么也得找个人陪我来
so I thought I had to have somebody...
你今天很美  你知道吗
You look great, you know?
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我可以带你入座吗
Can I show you to your seat?
好呀
That would be nice.
希望那会
Hopefully, it -- it...
卡塞尔
Castle.
你看上去就像是只迷路的小狗
You look like a lost puppy.
你的伴呢
Where's your date?
跟一个十几岁的小伙子去Lady Gaga的演唱会了
At a Lady Gaga concert with a teenage boy.
我怎么跟Lady Gaga比啊
How do I compete with that?
不  我真替你感到遗憾
Oh, no. I'm sorry.
我也觉得遗憾  我讨厌一个人参加婚礼
Yeah, me, too. I hate going to weddings alone.
也许咱俩可以给对方做个伴
Well, maybe we could be each other's plus one.
好主意  这样我们就不用
Yeah, and then avoid the stigma
坐在单身那桌受苦了
of sitting at the singles' table.
这样好极了  我非常乐意
Yes, that would be nice. I would like...
好的  好  好  好
Okay. Good, good, good.
看看他那样
Oh, look at him.
他看上去好开心啊
He looks so happy.
你们能来我太开心了
Hey. Oh, I'm so glad you're here.
我们怎么可能不来呢
Where else are we gonna be? Mwah.
你帅呆了
You look fantastic.
我们打扮得都不错哈
Yeah, we clean up pretty nice, huh?
珍妮  你美翻了
Oh, Jenny, you look amazing.
谢谢  里克
Thank you, Rick.
不不不  你现在还不能看她
No. No, no, no, no, no. You can't see her yet.
凯文  你真是个幸运的家伙
Kevin...you are a lucky man.
我也知道
Don't I know it?
准备好了吗  兄弟
Ready, bro?
好了
I think so.
好的  咱们礼堂里见
Okay. We're gonna see you in there.
好的
Okay.
你知道吗  我有点羡慕他
You know, I gotta say, I kind of envy him.
难说啊  卡塞尔  没准第三次就能美满了呢
Well, who knows, Castle? Maybe third time's the charm.
是啊
Yeah.
有可能
Could be.
-走吧  -好呀
- Shall we?  - Yeah.